Aditya Modi

1929 Plymouth Rd., Apt 3037 Ann Arbor, Michigan - 48105 (734) 881 0810 ⋈ admodi@umich.edu adityamodi.github.io

Overview

My core area of research is reinforcement learning with focus on sample complexity analyses. Broadly, I'm interested in developing methods with provable guarantees for sequential decision making frameworks like reinforcement learning, (contextual) bandits and general online learning.

Education

Sept '16-Present PhD, Computer Science, University of Michigan, Ann Arbor.

Advisors: Satinder Singh and Ambuj Tewari

Aug '12- May '16 Bachelor of Technology, Indian Institute of Technology, Kanpur, GPA – 9.4/10.0.

Major: Computer Science

Publications/Preprints

Working paper PREP: Credit Assignment without Exponentially Compounding Errors.

Alekh Agarwal, Hal Daume III, John Langford, Aditya Modi*, Amr Sharaf

* Alphabetical order.

AISTATS 2020 Sample Complexity of Learning with Linearly Combined Model Ensembles.

Aditya Modi, Nan Jiang, Ambuj Tewari, Satinder Singh

[link]

International Conference on Artificial Intelligence and Statistics (AISTATS), 2020.

AAAI 2020 Meta-Reasoning in Modular Software Systems via Reinforcement Learning.

A. Modi, D. Dey, A. Agarwal, A. Swaminathan, B. Nushi, S. Andrist, E. Horvitz

[link]

AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence (AAAI), 2020

Invited poster at ICML 2019 Workshop on Reinforcement Learning for Real Life

ICML 2019 Contextual Decision Processes using Generalized Linear Models.

Workshop, Aditya Modi and Ambuj Tewari

[link]

RLDM 2019 ICML 2019 Workshop on Reinforcement Learning for Real Life Preliminary version accepted to RLDM 2019, Montreal, Canada

ALT 2018 Markov Decision Processes with Continuous Side Information.

Aditya Modi, Nan Jiang, Satinder Singh, Ambuj Tewari

[link]

International Conference on Algorithmic Learning Theory (ALT) 2018

Research Experience

July-Oct 2018 Research Intern, Microsoft Research, Redmond.

Optimizing modular software pipelines via Reinforcement Learning

Mentors: Debadeepta Dey, Adith Swaminathan, Alekh Agarwal, Eric Horvitz

Worked on the application of contextual bandit, learning to search and policy search methods for input-adaptive parameter/algorithm selection across components in any modular software pipeline.

Sept-Dec 2016

Research Assistant, University of Michigan, Ann Arbor.

Data-dependent Importance weighted Active Learning

Advisors: Ambuj Tewari and Barzan Mozafari

Studied the sample complexity of importance-weighted active learning (IWAL) algorithms based on data-dependent complexity measures for bounded loss functions.

May-July 2015 Research Intern, Microsoft Research, Bangalore, India.

Active Semi-supervised Performance Evaluation

Advisor: Sundararajan Sellamanickam, Principal Applied Scientist.

[Report]

Proposed an estimation method for performance measures of black-box classifiers using scarcely labelled datasets for various non-decomposable performance measures (ROC curve, PR curve, F-measure).

Scholastic Achievements

- 2019 AAAI 2020 travel scholarship.
- 2019 NeurIPS 2019 best reviewer award.
- 2018, 2019 Rackham Travel Grant (ALT '18, ICML '19)
- May 2016 Travel Scholarship for MLSS Cadiz, 2016.
- 2013, 2015 Academic Excellence Award, IIT Kanpur.
 - 2014 Ram Parkash Chopra Memorial Scholarship, given for academic excellence, IIT Kanpur.
 - 2013 OPJEMS scholarship (awarded to 1 out of 850 students in the batch.)
 - 2012 Secured All India Rank 132 in IIT-JEE 2012 out of 0.5 million candidates.
 - 2012 Secured All India Rank 150 in AIEEE 2012 out of 1.2 million candidates.

Talks

March 2019 Contextual Decision Processes using Generalized Linear Models.

Speed Oral and poster, MSSISS 2019

March 2018 Markov Decision Processes with Continuous Side Information.

Oral presentation, MSSISS 2018

Teaching experience

- Winter 2017 Graduate Student Instructor, EECS 445 Machine Learning, Univ. of Michigan.
- Winter 2016 Student Mentor, CS 771 Machine Learning Techniques, IIT Kanpur.
 - Fall 2015 Teaching Assistant, ESO 207 Data Structures and Algorithms, IIT Kanpur.

Activities

Reviewer AAAI 2019, AISTATS 2019-20, ICML 2019-20, NeurIPS 2019 (Top reviewer)

2017, 2018 Co-organizer, Statistical Machine Learning Reading group, Univ. of Michigan.

Relevant Coursework

Theory Advanced Algorithms, Computational Complexity, Algorithmic Game Theory, Approximation Algorithms

Statistics Statistical Inference, Probability Theory, Large Sample Theory, Applied Probability and Stochastic Modeling.

Machine Machine Learning Techniques, Learning with Kernels, Online Learning and Optimization, Probabilistic Machine

Learning/Al Learning, Optimization Methods in Statistics, Advanced Artificial Intelligence, Applied Game Theory.